(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
チャンネル登録者 50万人記念 3rd Youtube Live
500,000 Subscribers Celebration 3rd Youtube Live
10月19日 21時〜 Suisei Channelにて
Oct 19th, 21:00~ on Suisei Channel
STARt IN THE SCREEEN!
COMET
NEXT COLOR PLANET
Hoshimachi Suisei 3rd Live
Make it to your best memories.
STARt IN THE SCREEEN!
Are You Ready...?
RAISE YOUR HANDS
A DECLARATION OF ×××
Let's get it going
始めよう
Let's begin
遠く 僕らの名のもとに
Far away, in the name of us
Bring it! Bring it down!
Cast off!
目障りな喧騒には蹴りつけた
I kicked away the eyesore of a noise
挑発するよ さらけ出せばいいな
I'll provoke you, you should just lay it all bare
極彩色 ただただ上るさ
Richly colored, we'll just keep climbing
It's only... できるの？できない？って
It's only... Can you do it? Or can't you?
口先 止まった愉快さがドッと
Lip service stopped, a sudden rush of pleasure
Prayers 捨て行けよ お前が
Prayers, throw it all away, you
真実を抉るように Play
As if to gouge out the truth, Play
真剣に Checkmate
Seriously, Checkmate
真実を刻むように Play
As if to carve the truth, Play
不遜 在るが儘しない Condition
Arrogant, not just staying as you are, Condition
僕らのシナリオは Never end
Our scenario Never ends
Aww!
煽り上げ 醒めるのは僕らさ
Stirring things up, it's us who wake up
魂を 覚まして 歌えよ
Awaken your soul and sing
I know, you know, we get to the top
3, 2, 1, JUMP!
煽り上げ 滲むほど熱い
Stirring things up, so hot it blurs
絶対的な 存在へと
Towards an absolute existence
I know, you know, A DECLARATION OF...
ここに 刻め
Carve it here
Ha!
ふてぶてしい声を枯らしても届く
Even if I wear out my impudent voice, it'll reach
どこからか 求めてる証に
As proof that someone, somewhere is searching
不条理 生きるのは辞めろよ
Stop living in absurdity
行き交うのが戯言が Fake
What passes by are just nonsense, fakes
上手く 揺るがせて 気付いて Feelings
Shake it up well, realize those feelings
Prayers あとは見下ろすだけ
Prayers, after that, just look down
真実を抉るように Play
As if to gouge out the truth, Play
未来の姿 Show in out
The figure of the future, Show in out
真実を刻むように Play
As if to carve the truth, Play
世界中を 切り裂いて行け
Go forth and tear the whole world apart
聞け！
Listen!
僕らのメモリーは Never die
Our memory will never die
RA RA RA...
Ah...
ARE WE AGAIN? 全ては僕らさ
ARE WE AGAIN? It's all us
魂を魂で掴んで
Grab your soul with your soul
I know, you know, we get to the top
ARE WE AGAIN? 信じろこの地で
ARE WE AGAIN? Believe in this place
負け知らずの微笑みを
With an undefeated smile
I know, you know
A declaration of...
ここに
Right here
聞け！
Listen!
画面の前のお前ら！
Everyone in front of your screens!
全員、頭振れー！
Everyone, headbang!
LET'S GET IT GO!! さぁ始めよう
LET'S GET IT GO!! Now let's begin
強固な僕らの名のもとに
Under our strong names
BIGGY BIGGY TA!!
CAST OUT!!
RAISE YOUR HANDS UP!
ARE WE AGAIN? 全ては僕らさ
ARE WE AGAIN? It's all us
魂を魂で掴んで
Grab your soul with your soul
I know, you know, we get to the top
ARE WE AGAIN? 信じろこの地で
ARE WE AGAIN? Believe in this place
絶対的な存在へと
Toward an absolute existence
I know, you know
A declaration of love
ここに
Right here
聞け！
Listen!
天球、彗星は夜を跨いで
作詞・作曲：キタニタツヤ
Celestial Sphere, Comet Straddles the Night
Lyrics & Composition: Kitani Tatsuya
灯りがひとつ灯った 灯った
A single light was lit, was lit
天を彩った 街が綺麗だ
The sky-colored town is beautiful
僕の吐いた白い息のように
Like the white breath I exhaled
消してしまえたらな
I wish I could make it disappear
押し殺して深く沈んだ
Suppressed and deeply sunk
泣き声さえ聞こえているから
Because I can even hear the sobbing
君を指差す不条理も
The absurdity that points at you
僕の青色で塗りつぶして
Paint it over with my blue
全部涙になって
Everything becomes tears
星の海を流れていった
And flowed through the sea of stars
果てしない闇の中に そっと頬を添えたらほら
In the endless darkness, if I softly press my cheek, look
彗星がひとつ 今日を飛んだ
A comet flew today
誰もいない夜の空を染めた
It dyed the empty night sky
深く静まった街の中へ
Into the deeply quiet town
降り注ぐのは 誰の悲しみだろう？
Whose sadness is it that's pouring down?
星はまたこうやって飛んだ
The stars flew like this again
今夜の不可確かさを払って
Wiping away tonight's uncertainty
いつかまた会えるなんて言えなかった
I couldn't say we'd meet again someday
星が降ったあとの街 僕らはまだ
The town after the stars fell, we are still...
黒く澄んだガランドの空を
The black and clear empty sky
ほうき星が彩るように
As the comets color it
君を指差す不条理も
The absurdity that points at you
僕の青色で塗りつぶして
Paint it over with my blue
君の涙をそっと
Softly, your tears
星の海に流し込むんだ
I'll pour them into the sea of stars
降り注ぐその光が 誰かをまた救うから
Because that pouring light will save someone again
彗星がひとつ 僕ら選ぶのなら
If a comet chooses us
この空を全部君にあげる
I'll give you this whole sky
...を引いて
...trailing behind
降り注ぐのは誰の悲しみだろう
Whose sadness is it that pours down?
星はまた弧を描いて飛んだ
The stars flew, drawing an arc again
街の視線を奪い去るように
As if to steal away the city's gaze
君とまた会えるなら僕は歌う
If I can meet you again, I'll sing
星の名前を一つ受け止めよう
I'll accept each and every star name
悲しみが溢れそうになること
That sadness is about to overflow
天球で離ればなれでも
Even if we are far apart in the celestial sphere
僕らは繋がってるから
Because we are connected
水星が頭上を飛んだ
A comet flew overhead
誰もいない夜の空を撫でた
Caressing the empty night sky
深く沈まった街の中へ
Into the deeply sunken city
降り注ぐのは誰の悲しみだろう
Whose sadness is it that pours down?
星はまた弧を描いて飛んだ
The stars flew, drawing an arc again
靄の彼方を少し晴らして
Clearing the distance beyond the mist a little
いつかまた会えるなんて言えなかった
I couldn't say that we'd meet again someday
星が降ったあとの街僕はずっと
The city after the stars fell, I've always
君の行方を探してた
been searching for your whereabouts
あなたに、感謝を込めて。
To you, with all my gratitude.
あー、皆さん！
Ah, everyone!
おー、見えました！
Oh, I see you!
見えてるよ、みんなのコメントも！
I can see them, all your comments too!
あー、はい！ということで始まりました！
Ah, yes! And so it has begun!
星街すいせい、50万人記念ライブー！
Hoshimachi Suisei's 500,000 subscriber anniversary live!
はい、ということでね、いつもの挨拶からやっていきたいと思います！
Yes, so, I'd like to start with my usual greeting!
彗星のごとく現れたスターの原石！
A diamond in the rough who appeared like a comet!
アイドルVTuberの星街すいせいです！
I'm the idol VTuber, Hoshimachi Suisei!
せーの、すいちゃーん？
One, two, Suichaan?
わーー！！
Waaa!!
すいちゃん、すいちゃん、すいちゃん...
Suichan, suichan, suichan...
今日最高！今日最高！今日最高！ありがとう！
Today's the best! Today's the best! Today's the best! Thank you!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ひー、いやー、疲れた。
Phew, boy, I'm tired.
2曲だけでこんなに疲れちゃった。
I got so tired from just two songs.
はい、ということで、2曲目は、Raise A Suilenの「A DECLARATION OF ×××」
Yes, so, the second song was Raise A Suilen's 'A DECLARATION OF ×××',
1曲目は、私星街すいせいの、「天球、彗星は夜を跨いで」でした！
And the first song was my own, 'Tenkyu, Suisei wa Yoru wo Mataide'!
どうだったかな？どうだったかな、皆さん？
How was it? How was it, everyone?
いや、本当に、なんか、あの、リハをですね、何回もやっていたんですけども、
Actually, really, I'd done rehearsals many times, but...
なんかやっと本番というか、本番が来てしまったという感じがちょっと、緊張がやばくて。
It feels like the actual performance is finally here, and I'm so nervous.
あ、もうこれもし本当に本番なのかみたいなのが、本当にちょっと緊張が声に現れていたかもしれませんが、
I was like, 'Wait, is this really the show?' so you might have heard the nerves in my voice,
あの、楽しく歌えたらいいなと思っております！
but I hope I can sing and have fun!
ということで、今回はですね、50万人、
So, this time, for reaching 500,000 subscribers,
チャンネル登録者数50万人を記念してこのライブを開催させていただきました！
I'm holding this live to celebrate reaching 500,000 subscribers!
50万人突破ありがとうございます！本当にありがとう、ありがとう、みんな！ありがとうみんな！
Thank you for 500,000 subscribers! Truly thank you, thank you, everyone! Thank you, everyone!
「最高だった」って、ありがとう！見えております、コメントが。
Someone said 'It was great', thank you! I can see the comments.
はい、えーと、そしてですね、あの、
Yes, uh, and also,
星街すいせい50万人記念ライブというタグがありまして、
we have the 'Hoshimachi Suisei 500,000 Anniversary Live' hashtag,
ちょっと、今出ますかね？あれ今出てる？ここらへんにきっと...
Wait, can we show it now? Is it up? It should be around here...
あ、出...え？出ない。
Ah, it's... eh? It's not appearing.
なんか、以前は出るって聞いてたんですけど、なんか今日出ないらしい！
I heard before that it would show up, but apparently it's not today!
え、すみません、あの、タイトルのほう、ここ、ここ、ここ、タイトルの通りに...
Uh, sorry, in the title, here, here, here, like in the title...
あの星街すいせい50万人記念ライブというハッシュタグがありますので、こちら、こちらツイートして！
We have that 'Hoshimachi Suisei 500,000 Anniversary Live' hashtag, so please tweet it!
ぜひツイートしてください！「出ないんかい」そう、「出ないんかい」。
Please do tweet it! 'It's not showing up?!' Yes, 'not showing up?!'
本当にすみませんって今言われました。
I was just told, 'Truly sorry'.
はい！ということで、えーと、実は今日、あのスペシャルな回として、そう、いろんなことを企てておりまして。
Yes! So, um, actually, today is a special occasion, and I've planned various things.
そのスペシャルなこと第、第1、第1として、ゲストが来てくれます！
The first of those special things is... we have a guest!
次の歌はゲストと一緒に歌いますよ！
I'll be singing the next song with a guest!
ということで！次の曲いってみましょう！
And so! Let's get into the next song!
Is this fate?
Is this Karma?
"cleave this silence"
月陽-ツキアカリ-
Tsukiakari (Moonlight)
作詞・作曲 みきとP
Music & Lyrics: Mikito P
たった一瞬の合図が
Just a single split-second signal
天命を呪いに変えた
turned destiny into a curse.
踵カンカンと響いた
The clicking of heels resounded,
あいつの足跡
those footsteps of theirs.
目線は深く いまして
With a gaze held deep,
曇天は不安定
the cloudy sky is unstable.
キッキッキと睨んだ
With a sharp, piercing glare,
眼差しは艶やかに
their gaze was captivating.
重ねた手のひらに見えた
In our joined palms, I saw...
覚悟という名の紅い
...the crimson color of what's called resolve...
魂
...the soul.
雷鳴
Thunder,
共鳴
resonance...
静寂を切り裂いて
tearing through the silence.
彷徨う心は叫び出す
A wandering heart begins to scream.
瞳の奥の
Deep within those eyes,
誓いの証明
the proof of a vow.
燃やせ
Burn...
紅く 紅く
...crimson, crimson.
闇に咲いた太陽
A sun blooming in the darkness.
淡淡 一夜明けは
Faintly, as the night breaks,
呪われた言の葉
cursed words...
眈眈 息吐けば
Vigilantly, with a sigh,
笑顔は消えていく
smiles begin to fade.
チチチとした内向きの
A clicking, inward-facing...
ため息は誰のせい
...sigh, whose fault is it?
今宵の光
Tonight's light...
滾らせた蒼白い
...made the pale blue...
魂
...soul boil.
愛も
Love,
夢も
dreams...
一悪の定め
...the fate of a single evil.
何人たりとも汚せない
No one can defile it.
たゆまぬ月の
Within the unwavering...
光の中で
...light of the moon,
何を 誰を 救うの
what and who are you saving?
悪意を飲んだ
Having swallowed malice,
名もなき野良猫
a nameless stray cat.
一つ二つと
One by one, two by two,
散りゆく花びら
the falling petals.
目眩い閃光が
A dazzling flash of light...
唯一の道を
...the only path...
照らした
...was illuminated.
愛も
Love,
夢も
dreams...
一悪の定め
...the fate of a single evil.
何人たりとも汚せない
No one can defile it.
たゆまぬ月の
Within the unwavering...
光の中で
...light of the moon,
誰を想うの
who are you thinking of?
雷鳴
Thunder,
共鳴
resonance...
静寂を切り裂いて
tearing through the silence.
彷徨う心は叫び出す
A wandering heart begins to scream.
瞳の奥の
Deep within those eyes,
誓いの証明
the proof of a vow.
燃やせ 燃やせ
Burn, burn...
闇に咲いた太陽
A sun blooming in the darkness.
PLATONIC GIRL
作詞・作曲：みきとP
Lyrics & Composition: Mikito-P
Don't touch me.
ついてこられるか この正真
Can you keep up with this reality?
仇なんて おまけにすぎないよ
Resentment is nothing more than a bonus.
目で見るリアルがすべてじゃない
The reality you see isn't everything.
平気に sick for you
Unfazed, I'm sick for you.
触れたい欲望 触れない愛情
Desire to touch, love that can't touch.
この距離 about 10 millimeter
This distance is about 10 millimeters.
薄い薄い膜を隔てて
Separated by a thin, thin membrane.
俺が愛だと叫んでみせても
Even if I shout that I am love,
NO WAY 狼なんで
NO WAY, because I'm a wolf.
NO WHAT? あの赤ずきん
NO WHAT? That Little Red Riding Hood.
TAKE ME 限界地帯に突入
TAKE ME, entering the limit zone.
甘くなくても溶けていくのさ
Even if it's not sweet, I'll melt away.
CRUSH ON YOU BABY!
プラトニックな プラトニックな エンドレス・ラブ
Platonic, platonic endless love.
触れないで 抱き合って テンダネス・ラブ
Don't touch me, hold me tight, tenderness love.
ツミサケ GIVE ME MORE (GIVE ME MORE)
Shout of sin, GIVE ME MORE (GIVE ME MORE).
ドキドキして致死量
Pounding heart, a lethal dose.
関節的 ありえない I LOVE YOU
Indirectly, an impossible I LOVE YOU.
BUT DON'T TOUCH ME
ここから先は立ち入り禁止
No entry beyond this point.
甘い果実に手を伸ばさないで
Don't reach out for the sweet fruit.
毒でいい子にお座りなさい
Sit down like a good boy with this poison.
NO WAY IN A WINK FOR YOU
醒めない衝動 禁断症状
Unawakening impulse, withdrawal symptoms.
この距離 about 1 millimeter
This distance is about 1 millimeter.
切ない切ない際どい関係
A painful, painful, risky relationship.
パンドラの箱 詰まっているのは
What's stuffed inside Pandora's box is,
NO WAY 底知れない友情
NO WAY, bottomless friendship.
NO WHAT? ハードオリオン
NO WHAT? Hard Orion.
KISS ME 見たいならどうぞ
KISS ME, if you want to see, then go ahead.
希望の先に残ったものは
What's left at the end of hope is,
TAKE ONE MORE MY LOVE!
プラトニックな プラトニックな エンドレス・ラブ
Platonic, platonic endless love.
シラケないで 遊ばせて テンダネス・ラブ
Don't spoil the fun, let me play, tenderness love.
だから BE QUIET (QUIET) QUIET (QUIET)
So BE QUIET (QUIET) QUIET (QUIET),
見つめ合っているだけ
We're just staring at each other.
完璧さ これ以上 求めないで
It's perfect, don't ask for any more.
STOP!
SIT DOWN!
SOFT SOFT
NO WAY 狼なんで
NO WAY, because I'm a wolf.
NO WHAT? あの赤ずきん
NO WHAT? That Little Red Riding Hood.
TAKE ME 限界地帯に突入
TAKE ME, entering the limit zone.
甘くなくても溶けていくのさ
Even if it's not sweet, I'll melt away.
ONE MORE TIME ARE YOU READY?
プラトニックな プラトニックな エンドレス・ラブ
Platonic, platonic endless love.
触れないで 抱き合って テンダネス・ラブ
Don't touch me, hold me tight, tenderness love.
ツミサケ GIVE ME MORE (GIVE ME MORE) ドキドキして致死量
Shout of sin, GIVE ME MORE (GIVE ME MORE), pounding heart, a lethal dose.
だから BE QUIET (QUIET) QUIET (QUIET) 見つめ合っているだけ
So BE QUIET (QUIET) QUIET (QUIET), we're just staring at each other.
それだけが PLATONIC PLATONIC
That alone is PLATONIC PLATONIC.
二人の愛のパルス
The pulse of our love.
関節的 ありえない I LOVE YOU
Indirectly, an impossible I LOVE YOU.
BUT DON'T TOUCH ME
TRIal HEART ～恋の違反チケット～
作詞：松井洋平 / 作曲：本多友紀
TRIal HEART ~Love Violation Ticket~
Lyrics: Yohei Matsui / Composition: Yuki Honda
アイドルの恋は、許されないの？
Is an idol's love not allowed?
弁護します！
I'll defend you!
告訴するわ！
I'll prosecute you!
恋愛裁判！
Romance trial!
開廷です！
Court is in session!
無罪でいいんです
Not guilty is fine
トキメク気持ちは
These throbbing feelings
有罪なのです
Are actually guilty
アイドルなのですから
Since I'm an idol
好きになっちゃえば
If I end up liking someone
抗えない
I can't resist
乙女の権利ね
It's a maiden's right
素敵だわ
It's wonderful
恋愛禁止 まだ早すぎね
Romance ban? It's still too early
異議あり！ どっち？
Objection! Which one?
却下！
Overruled!
恋する女の子のハート
A girl in love's heart
罪なのでしょうか？
Is it a sin?
Trial Heart... 純粋な気持ちに
Trial Heart... To pure feelings
嘘はついちゃダメ
You mustn't lie
恋がハイスピードで
Love, at high speed
ルール追い越したら
If it overtakes the rules
耳を持たない気なら
If you won't listen
説得は無駄ね
Persuasion is useless
大好きだもん！
Because I love you!
無罪じゃなくちゃね
Must be not guilty
恋は自由でしょ？
Love is free, isn't it?
有罪で決まり
Guilty, it's decided
情状酌量の余地なし
No room for extenuating circumstances
これって結構
This is quite a
大問題
Big problem
想いに正直
Honest with feelings
素晴らしいわ
It's wonderful
決めごとは絶対 もっともなのよね
Rules are absolute, that's reasonable
異議あり！ どっち？
Objection! Which one?
却下！
Overruled!
恋する瞳 周りが
Eyes in love, everything around
見えなくなるんでしょ？
You stop seeing them, right?
危険だって知っていて
Knowing it's dangerous
何故落ちるのでしょう？
Why do we fall?
恋がノンストップで
Love, non-stop
ルート決めちゃったの
It's decided its route
待っても制止を越え
Wait? It's past the stop
だったら免罪？
Then, exoneration?
純情揺れちゃう
Pure feelings are wavering
異議あり！ 弁護人の主張には根拠がありません！
Objection! The defense's claim has no basis!
異議あり！ 検察官の主張は課題があります！
Objection! The prosecutor's claim is problematic!
ねえ どっちが正しいの？
Hey, which one is right?
愛情の 恋の悩みは
Affection's, romance's troubles
心で審議です
Deliberate them in your heart
天使と悪魔の主張
Claims of angel and devil
裁判は踊る
The trial dances
恋する女の子のハート
A girl in love's heart
罪なのでしょうか？
Is it a sin?
純粋な気持ちに
To pure feelings
嘘はついちゃダメ
You mustn't lie
恋がハイスピードで
Love, at high speed
ルール追い越したの
It overtook the rules
耳を持たない気なら
If you won't listen
説得は無駄ね
Persuasion is useless
駆け引きの時間
Time for tactics
傾く心 ギルティ
A leaning heart, guilty
恋こそ甘美な罪ね
Love is indeed a sweet sin
はいー！
Yes!
はぁ、すごーい！
Phew, amazing!
はぁ、お疲れ様です...
Phew, good job everyone...
はぁ、全員疲れてるｗ めっちゃ疲れたｗ
やばい、すごい、本当に頑張ったｗ
Everyone is exhausted lol. I'm so tired.
Crazy, amazing, we really worked hard.
はい、ということで。えー、ゲストはかなたとトワです！
Alright then. Well, the guests are Kanata and Towa!
お邪魔しまーす！ お邪魔しまーす！
Glad to be here! Glad to be here!
いや、もうね。この3人で一緒にたくさんダンス練習してきました。
Man, seriously. The three of us
practiced dancing together so much.
ねー、本当に。
Yeah, really.
今日ね、その成果が出せたのではないかなと、思っております！
I think we were able to show the results of that today!
出せましたね。
We certainly did.
はい、ということで。かなたとは『ミキトP』の『月光り』、
トワとは『和風』の『プラトニック・ガール』、
Right then. With Kanata it was Mikito-P's "Moonlight",
with Towa it was the Japanese-style "Platonic Girl",
3人で『プリパラ』より、『TRIal HEART』を躍らせていただきましたー！
and the three of us danced
"TRIal HEART" from "PriPara"!
いかがだったでしょうかー！
How was it?!
いや、ダンスがね。難しかった。
Man, the dancing... It was hard.
かっこよかったー。
It was so cool.
本当に難しくて、なんか、あの、こ、ここ？
It was really hard, like, uh, "this part"?
「どうしようか」って結構ね、リハーサルでもね。
Like, "what should we do?", we discussed that a lot in rehearsals.
そう。ここ、ここじゃあ座ろう、とかさ。すごい考えて。
Right. Like, "let's sit down here/there". We thought about it so much.
あ、ね！
Ah, right!
あとはね、ね！
And also, right!
ね、もう、トワ様と一緒に…
Right, together with Towa-sama...
本当に、最後の最後までダンスを…
Really, right up until the very end, the dance...
ダンスをね。
The dance, right.
そう、ここはね、こうやってこうやってこうだよ、みたいな。
Yeah, like, "This part goes like this, this, and this."
そうだね、運動音痴が、すいちゃんのね、すごいきれいな…
Right, my lack of coordination... Suisei's really beautiful...
そう、めっちゃ最後まで教えてもらってたんだよね。
Yeah, she was teaching us right until the end.
ギリギリまでやってます！
We're doing it until the very last minute!
はい！
Yes!
どうだったかな？ ダンスまでね、ちょっと頑張ってみましたけれども。
How was it? We tried our best with the dancing too.
そう、トワ様もダンスすごかったって。
Yeah, Towa-sama's dancing was amazing too.
よかったー！
I'm so glad!
すごい！
Amazing!
トレンド1位！ ありがとう！
Trending #1! Thank you!
あー！ おめでとう！
Ah! Congratulations!
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
本当に本当におめでとう、すいちゃん！
Truly, congratulations, Sui-chan!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
はい、ということで、二人をお呼びいたしましたけれども。
Alright, so, I invited these two here.
はい！
Yes!
実は…
Actually...
お？
Oh?
ゲストが！
There's a guest!
おお？ おおー！
Oh? Oh!
ということで、このあともお楽しみに！
So, please look forward to what's coming up next!
イエーイ！
Yay!
ここから… ここから… だんだん… 次の曲、行ってまいりましょう！
From here... from here... gradually... let's head into the next song!
はい！
Yes!
強くなれる理由を知った 僕を連れて進め
I found a reason to be strong, take me with you and move forward.
紅蓮華
作詞：LiSA / 作曲：草野華余子
Gurenge
Lyrics: LiSA / Composition: Kayoko Kusano
進め
Move forward
泥だらけの走馬灯に酔う こわばる心
Drunk on a mud-stained kaleidoscope, a stiffened heart.
震える手は掴みたいものがある それだけさ
My trembling hands have something they want to grasp, that's all.
夜の匂いに空睨んでも
Even if I glare at the sky in the scent of the night,
変わっていけるのは自分自身だけ それだけさ
The only one who can change is myself, that's all.
強くなれる理由を知った 僕を連れて進め
I found a reason to be strong, take me with you and move forward.
どうしたって！ 消せない夢も 止まれない今も
No matter what! A dream that can't be erased, a present that can't stop.
誰かのために強くなれるなら ありがとう 悲しみよ
If I can become strong for someone's sake, thank you, sadness.
世界に打ちのめされて負ける意味を知った
I learned the meaning of defeat after being beaten down by the world.
紅蓮の華よ咲き誇れ！ 運命を照らして
Crimson lotus flower, bloom in full! Illuminate my destiny.
イナビカリの雑音が耳を刺す 戸惑う心
The noise of lightning stabs my ears, a bewildered heart.
優しいだけじゃ守れないものがある？ わかってるけど
Are there things that can't be protected by kindness alone? I know, but...
水面下で絡まる善悪 透けて見える偽善に天罰
Good and evil entangled beneath the surface, divine punishment for visible hypocrisy.
Tell me why, I don't need you!
逸才の花より 挑み続け咲いた一輪が美しい
More beautiful than a flower of talent is a single blossom that bloomed through constant challenge.
乱暴に敷き詰められたトゲだらけの道も
Even a path roughly covered with thorns,
本気の僕だけに現れるから 乗り越えてみせるよ
Will only appear to the serious me, so I'll show you I can overcome it.
簡単に片付けられた守れなかった夢も
Even the dreams that couldn't be protected, easily brushed aside,
紅蓮の心臓に根を癒やし この地に宿ってる
Heal their roots in a crimson heart and dwell in this land.
Ah...
強くなれる理由を知った 僕を連れて進め
I found a reason to be strong, take me with you and move forward.
どうしたって！ 消せない夢も 止まれない今も
No matter what! A dream that can't be erased, a present that can't stop.
誰かのために強くなれるなら ありがとう 悲しみよ
If I can become strong for someone's sake, thank you, sadness.
世界に打ちのめされて負ける意味を知った
I learned the meaning of defeat after being beaten down by the world.
紅蓮の華よ咲き誇れ！ 運命を照らして
Crimson lotus flower, bloom in full! Illuminate my destiny.
運命を照らして
Illuminate my destiny.
Believe again
きっと一人じゃない 夢の中へ Go!
I'm surely not alone, go into the dream!
迷いながら Ready? GO!
While being lost, Ready? GO!
やっとね 気が付いたみたい
It seems I finally noticed
あなたの中の消えない光
the light inside you that doesn't go out.
JUST LIGHT!
どこへ行っても それは
Wherever you go, it is
希望という名の羽根だから BYE HIGH!
the wings called hope, so BYE HIGH!
強さを求めたら
If you seek strength,
弱さも受け入れてみようよ
try accepting your weaknesses too.
MY FAULT!
余裕がない心じゃ
With a heart that has no room,
夢は遠ざかるのかも
the dream might drift away.
生まれ変わろう
Let's be reborn.
新しくなれ 殻を破って
Become new, break out of the shell.
進めるできるね できるよ 次の場所へと
You can advance, you can do it, to the next place.
もっと踊りたい
I want to dance more,
I want to dance more.
BETTER! YEAH! DANCE! YEAH!
止まらないよ DAS BELIEVE!
I won't stop, DAS BELIEVE!
BELIEVE! BELIEVE!
AGAIN! AGAIN!
すべてを抱きしめながら
While embracing everything,
BELIEVE! BELIEVE!
AGAIN! AGAIN!
また始まるんだ ON MY SOUL
It's starting again, ON MY SOUL.
本気だって言わなくたって きっと伝わるよ
Even if I don't say I'm serious, it will surely be conveyed.
何度でも熱くなれ 自由になれ
Become passionate again and again, become free.
BELIEVE! BELIEVE!
AGAIN! AGAIN!
また始まるんだ YEAH! YEAH! YEAH!
It's starting again, YEAH! YEAH! YEAH!
冒険は終わらないよ LET'S GO!
The adventure never ends, LET'S GO!
どんなに楽しい場所も
No matter how fun a place is,
永遠じゃないからね そろそろ出発
it's not eternal, so it's time to set off.
TIME OVER!
どこへ行っても胸に
Wherever I go, in my heart,
温かい思い出が眠る MY LIFE
warm memories lie dormant, MY LIFE.
重くて飛べなかった
It was too heavy to fly,
心脱ぎ捨てて軽やかに
casting off my heart and being light.
STEP OUT!
変化を受け入れよう
Let's accept change,
夢も進化の時だった
it was a time for dreams to evolve too.
分かってきたね
You've come to understand, right?
前を向いた そして思いのままに
I looked forward, and then as I thought.
進めるできるね できるよ 次の場所へと
You can advance, you can do it, to the next place.
今日も踊って
Dance today too,
dance today too.
LET'S! YEAH! DANCE! YEAH!
止まらないよ DAS BELIEVE!
I won't stop, DAS BELIEVE!
BELIEVE! BELIEVE!
AGAIN! AGAIN!
誰より激しく生きて
Live more intensely than anyone else
Believe, believe again (again, again!)
誇り残さないで
Don't leave any pride behind
待ってなんて言わないよ
I won't say "wait"
みんなそれぞれの
Everyone has their own...
夢があって未来へと向かうだけさ
...dreams and just heads towards the future
Believe, believe again (again, again!)
誇り残さないで
Don't leave any pride behind
さあ遊びじゃないよ
Now, this isn't a game
Try Let's Go!
Shout! Shout! Shout! My Soul!
Now We Can Go! We Can Go!
もっと信じて
Believe more
We Can Fly! We Can Fly!
そうどんな夢も
Yes, any dream
We Can Go! We Can Go!
もっと信じて
Believe more
We Can Fly! We Can Fly!
さあどんな夢も
Now, any dream
Oh yeah!
Believe, believe again (again, again!)
Stop, stop, stop 止まらないよ Dance
Stop, stop, stop, the dance won't stop
Believe, believe again (again, again!)
すべてを抱きしめながら
While embracing everything
Believe, believe again (again, again!)
また始まるんだ
It's starting again
Shout My Soul!
本気だって言わなくたってきっと伝わるよ
Even without saying I'm serious, it'll surely reach you
何度でも熱くなれ 自由になれ
Get passionate over and over again, be free
Believe, believe again (again, again!)
また始まるんだ
It's starting again
さあ遊びじゃないよ
Now, this isn't a game
Let's Go!
Above and far, 終わらないよ
Above and far, it won't end
Let's Go!
3 2 1 Go!
はい！ということで、次のゲストはまつりちゃーん！
Yes! So, our next guest is Matsuri-chan!
いぇーい！
Yay!
ふー！すごーい！
Phew! Amazing!
やばい！めちゃめちゃ緊張したー！
Oh my god! I was so nervous!
間違えちゃった、実を言うと私。
I messed up, to be honest.
まつりも！
Matsuri too!
バレないようにしなきゃ、
I was like "don't let them notice,
バレないようにしなきゃと思ってたんだけど。
don't let them notice."
ということでね、今日これアイドル衣装で。
So, we're in idol costumes today.
そうなんです！お揃いで！
That's right! We're matching!
こんなお帽子もつけてね！
And wearing these hats too!
かわいいー！一緒に踊らせていただきました！
Cute! Thank you for letting me dance with you!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
はい！ということで、歌ったのはSaint Snowの「Believe again」でしたー！
Yes! So, that was "Believe again" by Saint Snow!
いぇーい！まつちゃんとも本当にもうすごいダンスの練習を。
Yay! I practiced dancing so much with Matsu-chan.
いや、本当にしました！
No, we really did!
最初、もう全然できなくて。
At first, we couldn't do it at all.
「どうやるのこれ！？」みたいな。
Like "How do you even do this!?"
「ここ、ここ！あ、こうやって！」みたいな。
"Here, here! Ah, like this!"
「移動忘れた！」
"I forgot the movement!"
「ごめん！」とかめっちゃあったんだけど。
"Sorry!" There was a lot of that.
あれ？私、大丈夫、ちゃんと踊れてた？
Wait, did I dance okay? Was I proper?
うん！めちゃめちゃ良かった！さすが！
Yeah! It was so good! As expected!
良かったー！安心しました。実は途中でイヤモニが外れてて。
I'm glad! I'm relieved. To be honest, my in-ear monitor came off halfway.
そうなの！？
Really!?
そう！半分以上根性で。
Yes! More than half was just pure willpower.
ああ〜。何か音、ちょっと返ってくるの怖いんだけど。
Ah~. I'm a bit scared of the sound coming back...
でも何かあの、踊りは本当に凄く爽快。
But you know, the dance was really exhilarating.
何か本当にやりきったっていう気持ちがでかい！
I feel a huge sense of accomplishment!
いや本当に。いや、ありがとうございました！
Truly. No, thank you!
まつりちゃんはね、おまつりちゃんの誕生日だったっけ？
Matsuri-chan, was it your birthday?
19日かな？
The 19th?
そう、その時にあの呼んでいただきまして。
Yes, you invited me then.
その時から一緒に歌って踊りたいっていう気持ちがあったので。
Since then, I've wanted to sing and dance together.
今日ここで叶えられて嬉しかった！
I was so happy to make that come true here today!
ありがとうございましたー！良かったー！
Thank you very much! I'm so glad!
次はまつりのチャンネルでも一緒に歌って踊りたい！
Next time, I want to sing and dance together on Matsuri's channel too!
やりましょう！歌って踊りたい！
Let's do it! I want to sing and dance!
何たって我々はアイドルだから！
After all, we're idols!
Because we're idols!
その時はアイドルではない、今夜はアイドルではない。
At that time we're not idols... tonight we're not idols?
今夜が凄すぎて、語彙が出てこなかった。
Tonight was so amazing, I ran out of words.
あー面白い。すいちゃんありがとう！
Ah, that's funny. Thanks Sui-chan!
ありがとうございましたー！ということで、実はまだゲストがいます。
Thank you very much! So, actually, there's still more guests.
おお！
Oh!
では！次の曲いってみましょう！
Then! Let's go to the next song!
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
見上げれば青空
Looking up, the blue sky
鏡の鳥
作詞：桑原聖 (Arte Refact) 作曲・編曲：高橋諒 (Void_Chords)
Mirror Bird
Lyrics: Satoru Kuwabara (Arte Refact) / Music & Arrangement: Ryo Takahashi (Void_Chords)
その向こうに
To the other side of that...
行きたいの
...I want to go.
焦がれれば
The more I yearn...
焦がれるほど
...the more I yearn...
遠く
...the further it feels.
翼なら あるのに
Even though I have wings,
ひらき方 忘れてしまった
I've forgotten how to open them.
風に乗る 術さえも
Even the way to ride the wind,
今では もう
is now...
また一つ
Once again...
ひらりと落ちた
...fluttering down...
その羽を あなたは拾い上げ
...you pick up that feather.
臆病な 私を誘うように
As if inviting my cowardly self,
宙に投げたんだ
you threw it into the air.
ゆっくりと
Slowly,
手を広げて
opening my hands.
この羽で 生きていけるなら
If I can live with these wings,
息を吸って
taking a breath,
身体中 細胞が 憶えているよ
every cell in my body remembers.
あなたが 言うから
Because you say so.
砂を舞う
Dancing in the sand,
あの子は 何よりも
that child, more than anything else,
綺麗に見えた
looked beautiful.
そのせいで
Because of that,
誰も届かないところへ
to a place where no one can reach.
足元に
At my feet,
ひらりと舞った
fluttering down,
羽が今 あの子に重なった
a feather now overlaps with that child.
どこまでも
Endlessly,
自由に飛べるように
so that I can fly freely,
歌を添えるよ
I'll offer a song.
ゆっくりと
Slowly,
手を広げて
opening my hands.
この空の この世界の 向こうより
From beyond this sky, this world,
あの姿 遠ざかって 見えなくなっても
even if that figure fades away and can no longer be seen,
ここから 歌うよ
I will sing from here.
籠を飛び出して
Flying out of the cage,
自由を背にした
with freedom on my back.
鳥が奏でる音を今
Now, the sound that the bird plays,
私は辿って
I follow,
誰も辿って
everyone follows,
歌う
and sing.
どこまでも高く
Higher and higher,
響いて
echoing.
いのち
作詞・作曲：瀬名航
Inochi
Lyrics & Composition: Wataru Sena
息をしている
I am breathing
君は生きている
You are alive
当然のこと
It's only natural
誰も疑わないの
No one doubts it
息をしている
I am breathing
目に見えている
I can see it
正常の裏側は
The flip side of normal
私にとっての何か
Is something to me
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heartbeat is thumping
叩かれても 腐らずに
Even if I'm struck down, I won't rot
ここで歌うよ
I'll sing here
ボタンひとつのいのち
A life of a single button
最後まで私のこと届けてくれるの？
Will you deliver me to the very end?
消えてしまいそうなの
It feels like I might disappear
わかってよ わかってよ ねえ
Understand me, please understand me
本当のことなの
It's the truth
恋と推しは違うんでしょ？
Love and being a fan are different, right?
君が忘れちゃったら
If you forget
私は居なくなるの
I will cease to exist
いのちのような夢を見てるよ
I'm dreaming a dream like life
またね バイバイ
See you later, bye bye
息をしている
I am breathing
だから生きている
That's why I'm alive
自己証明を欲しがって
Desiring self-proof
欲しがっているんだ
I am longing for it
音が止まって
When the sound stops
動かなくなって
And I cease to move
そんな私を
A version of me like that
君は笑ってくれるかな
Will you smile for me?
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heartbeat is thumping
嫌われても 腐らずに
Even if I'm hated, I won't rot
ここで歌うよ
I'll sing here
はい！ということで！ありがとうございましたー！
Yes! So! Thank you very much!
はい、最後のゲスト、そらちゃんと、AZKiちゃんでしたー！
Yes, our final guests were Sora-chan and AZKi-chan!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
ありがとう！おめでとう！
Thank you! Congratulations!
もうね、ほんと、そらちゃんとは、えっと、ディジレールの、えっと...
You know, really, with Sora-chan, well, at Digirail...
大丈夫？大丈夫、大丈夫だよ。
Are you okay? You're okay, it's okay.
歌わせてもらって、AZKiちゃんとは、イノチを一緒に歌わせていただきました。
We got to sing together, and with AZKi-chan, we sang "Inochi" together.
はい、もうそらちゃんとも、なんか、すごい、なんか感慨深いし、
Yes, it's just so moving to be with Sora-chan,
AZKiちゃんとも今ここに立ってるのすごい感慨深いし。
and it's also so moving to be standing here with AZKi-chan right now.
あのね、本当に、あの『いのち』っていう曲がですね、私が、あの、イノナカミュージックに入って、
You know, really, that song "Inochi" was from when I joined Inonaka Music,
あの、初めての、なんか、出させてもらったライブ？
it was the first live I got to perform in, right?
ね？ね、あの、歌わせていただいたんですけど、その時も泣いて歌えなくなって...
Right? I got to sing it then too, but I started crying and couldn't sing...
感極まっちゃって、本当に、あの、すみません、ティッシュでズビー、ズビー。
I got overwhelmed, really... sorry, [sniffling with a tissue] *sniff*, *sniff*.
いやー、本当、もうなんか本当に、なんだろう、すごい、お二人と一緒に歌えてよかったなって本当に思いました。
Wow, really... I'm just so glad I could sing with both of you. I really am.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
いや、本当にもう、あの、すいちゃんの方から今回、お誘いいただいて。
No, really, Suisei-chan was the one who invited us this time.
本当にすいちゃんと会うのも...
And meeting Suisei-chan too...
お久しぶりで、もう1年以上ぶりぐらいに、やっとね、
it's been so long, like over a year, and we finally,
一緒にこうやって同じステージに立つことができて、本当に嬉しい、
got to stand on the same stage like this. I'm so happy,
本当に素敵な時間でした. すいちゃんありがとう。
it was a truly wonderful time. Thank you, Suisei-chan.
なんか、あの、何かが、ちょっと何かが違っていたら多分私はまだどこかでAZKiちゃんと一緒にどっかのステージで一緒に歌ってたかもしれないなって。
I felt like, if something had been just a little bit different, maybe I'd still be singing with AZKi-chan on a stage somewhere.
でも今ね、私はもうイノナカミュージック抜けて、ホロライブとして今ね、あの、居させていただいているので、
But now, I've left Inonaka Music and I'm here as a member of Hololive,
なんかこういう機会でね、こういう時に歌えて本当に嬉しかったですね。ありがとうございました。
so being able to sing like this on an occasion like this made me really happy. Thank you so much.
そらちゃんも！大丈夫？この後歌える？
Sora-chan too! Are you okay? Can you sing after this?
すいちゃん可愛いよ、今日も可愛いよ。
Suisei-chan, you're cute, you're cute today too.
ありがとうございます。本当にお二人ともありがとうございましたー！
Thank you. Thank you so much, both of you!
おめでとう！頑張ってね！
Congratulations! Good luck!
頑張りまーす！
I'll do my best!
はい、ということで、いや、やってまったよ。感極まってしまった本当に。
Alright, well, wow, I did it. I really got overwhelmed.
はぁ、まあねこれも、あの、生の醍醐味ということで。
*sigh* Well, I guess that's the charm of a live performance.
あ、ということで、これから、えっと、最後の曲を歌うんですけれども、
Ah, so, I'm going to sing the final song now,
その前に皆ちょっと気になってることがあったと思うんですけど、あの...
but before that, I think everyone might be wondering about something, um...
グッズ！グッズですよ！グッズ！ちょっと出ますかね？ドドン！
Merch! It's the merch! Merch! Can we see it? Ta-da!
星街すいせい 50万人記念ライブ
10月19日 販売開始
記念グッズ販売
★手島nari先生 B2タペストリー
★星街すいせい 今日もかわいいアクリルスタンド＜再販＞
★星街すいせい 描き下ろしフェイスタオル
★星街すいせい 描き下ろしTシャツ
Hoshimachi Suisei 500,000 Subscribers Anniversary Live
Sales start October 19th
Anniversary Merch Sales
★Teshima Nari-sensei B2 Tapestry
★Hoshimachi Suisei "Kyomo Kawaii" Acrylic Stand
★Hoshimachi Suisei Newly Illustrated Face Towel
★Hoshimachi Suisei Newly Illustrated T-shirt
あ、出ました！星街すいせい50万人記念ライブの記念グッズが販売されます。
Ah, there it is! Anniversary merch for the Hoshimachi Suisei 500,000 Subscribers Anniversary Live will be on sale.
えー、手島nari先生、B2タペストリー、
Um, Teshima Nari-sensei's B2 tapestry,
星街すいせい、今日もかわいいアクリルスタンドの、こちら再販、
the Hoshimachi Suisei "Kyomo Kawaii" acrylic stand—this one's a reprint—
星街すいせいの描き下ろしフェイスタオル、星街すいせい描き下ろしTシャツがですね...
the Hoshimachi Suisei newly illustrated face towel, and the Hoshimachi Suisei newly illustrated T-shirt...
この後、配信終わりの10時から、配信じゃね、販売が開始されますので、
Sales will start at 10:00 after the stream ends—not the stream, the sales—
ぜひぜひチェックしてください。次の画像行くかな？
so please be sure to check them out. Can we go to the next image?
お！こちら、見て！ねぇ、見て、このT-T-T-Tシャツ、Tシャツ。
Oh! Look at this! Hey, look at this T-T-T-T-shirt, the T-shirt.
Tシャツやばくない？ちょっとめっちゃお洒落なんだけど。お洒落、お洒落。
Isn't the T-shirt crazy? It's like, super stylish. Stylish, stylish.
ねぇ、あの、Tシャツ、あ、これTシャツアップにできますか？
Hey, um, the T-shirt... ah, can we zoom in on the T-shirt?
できるできる？ちょっともうちょっとさ、デザインを見せたいんだわ、めちゃめちゃ。できるかな？
Can we? I really want to show the design a bit more. Can we do that?
あ、ありがとうございます。星街すいせい描き下ろしフェイスタオル、星街すいせい描き下ろしTシャツはですね、
Ah, thank you. For the Hoshimachi Suisei newly illustrated face towel and the Hoshimachi Suisei newly illustrated T-shirt...
私が、あ、ありがとうございます！手書きさせていただきました。すげーかっこよくない？お洒落でしょ？
I drew them by hand... ah, thank you! Isn't it super cool? It's stylish, right?
あ、そう、忘れてたんですけど、言うの。今回のですね、あの、ライブのタイトルが、『STARt IN THE SCREEEN!』となっております。
Ah, right, I forgot to mention it. The title of this live is "STARt IN THE SCREEEN!"
このね、あの、『E』のところが3つ連なって音符みたいになってる、これかっこいいでしょ？
You see, these three "E"s lined up look like musical notes, isn't that cool?
これ思いついた時私、あ、天才だなって思ったの。
When I thought of this, I was like, "Ah, I'm a genius."
ありがと、みんなありがと、ぜひぜひ買ってください。
Thanks, thanks everyone, please buy them.
えーっとこの後10時から販売開始です。あとは、えーっと、星街すいせい50万人記念ライ...あれ？
Um, sales start at 10:00. Also, um, Hoshimachi Suisei 500,000 Subscribers Anniversary Li— wait?
ちょっと待って。あ、もしかしてもう10時になってる？
Wait a sec. Ah, could it be 10:00 already?
あ、じゃあもう開始してます。もう開始してます。ぜひ買ってください。
Oh, then sales have already started. They've already started. Please buy them!
あとはあの星街すいせい50万人記念ライブのハッシュタグをつけて、ぜひぜひたくさんツイートしてくださいね！ありがとうございます！
Also, please tweet a lot using the hashtag for the Hoshimachi Suisei 500,000 Subscribers Anniversary Live! Thank you!
はい！では！そんなこんなで！
Okay! Now! Without further ado!
最後にもう一曲、歌わせていただきたいと思います。
I'd like to sing one last song.
50万人に来るまで、本当にあの、簡単な道ではなかったんですけれども、
Until reaching 500,000, it really wasn't an easy path, but...
こうして、みんなの前で、こんな素敵なライブをやらせていただける、
...to be able to perform such a wonderful live in front of everyone like this...
そんな、そんな人間になれて、
...to have become that kind of person,
そんなアイドルになれて本当に良かった。
and that kind of idol, I'm truly glad.
VTuber続けてて、本当に良かったなと思います。
I'm really glad I continued being a VTuber.
本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
これからもどうぞ、星街すいせいの応援をよろしくお願いいたします。
Please continue to support Hoshimachi Suisei.
では、最後の曲聴いてください。
Now, please listen to the final song.
ダイアモンド クレバス。
Diamond Crevasse.
ダイアモンド クレバス
作詞：hal / 作曲：菅野よう子
Diamond Crevasse
Lyrics: hal / Composition: Yoko Kanno
神様に恋をしていた頃は
When I was in love with God...
こんな別れが来るとは思ってなかったよ
...I never thought a parting like this would come.
もう二度と触れられないのなら
If I can never touch you again...
せめて最後に、もう一度抱きしめてほしかったよ
...I wanted you to hold me one last time at the end.
It's long good-bye
サヨナラ サヨナラ
Goodbye, goodbye.
何度だって自分に無情に言い聞かせて
No matter how many times I heartlessly tell myself.
手を振るのは優しさだよね
Waving your hand is an act of kindness, right?
今強さが欲しい
Right now, I want strength.
あなたに出会い 輝いてあたしは生まれ
Meeting you, I shone and I was born.
愛すればこそ 愛されればこそ
Only because I love, only because I'm loved...
希望のない奇跡を待ってどうなるの
...what happens when I wait for a hopeless miracle?
涙ににじむ 星の瞬きは今...
The twinkling of stars blurred by tears is now...
忘れないよ あなたの温もりも
I won't forget your warmth...
その優しさも すべて包んでくれた両手も
...or your kindness, or the hands that embraced everything.
It's long good-bye
サヨナラ サヨナラ
Goodbye, goodbye.
愛しい人
My beloved...
あなたがいたから歩いてこれた
...it's because you were here that I could walk this far.
独りなんかじゃなかったよね
I wasn't alone, was I?
今答えが欲しい
Right now, I want an answer.
燃えるような流星 捕まえて火を灯して
Catch a burning meteor and light a fire.
愛していたい 愛されていたい
I want to love, I want to be loved.
冷えた身体ひとつで世界はどうなるの
What will happen to the world with only this chilled body?
走り続けてた虚勢が溶けていく
The bravado I kept running with is melting away...
どうしてなの
Why is it...
涙あふれて
...tears are overflowing...
止められない
...and I can't stop them.
ダイアモンド クレバス
Diamond Crevasse
あなたに出会い　星は輝き　新しく生まれて
Meeting you, the stars shone, and I was born anew
愛すればこそ
Precisely because I love you
いればこそ
Precisely because you are here
希望のない奇跡を待って
Waiting for a miracle without hope
どうなるの？
What will happen?
涙に滲む
Blurring into tears
星の瞬きは
The twinkling of the stars
もし生まれ変わって　また巡り会えるなら
If I were reborn and could meet you again
その時もきっと
Surely, even then
私を見つけ出して
Please find me
もう二度と離さないで
Never let me go again
捕まえてて
Keep holding on to me
一人じゃないと
Tell me I'm not alone
囁いて
Whisper it to me
ほしいの
I want you to
チャンネル登録者 50万人記念 3rd Youtube Live
500,000 Subscribers Commemoration 3rd YouTube Live
10月19日 21時～ Suisei Channelにて
October 19th from 21:00 on Suisei Channel